omron-healthcare.it 2016-06-17

# Privacy and cookie policy

#### What information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you:  
• Information that you provide by filling in forms on any of the Omron websites. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use the Website, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by Omron, and when you report a problem with the Website.

•If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence. We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

•Details of your visits to the Website and the resources that you access.

•Details about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration. This is statistical data about the Website users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

#### Cookies

The Website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of the Website. A cookie is a small file that is sent together with pages of the Website and stored by your web browser on the harddisk of your computer. If a cookie has been stored, the information contained therein can be send back to our servers during your next visit to the Website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse the Website and also allows us to improve it.

#### Permanent cookies

By using permanent cookies we can recognize you at your next visit to the Website. We use these cookies to provide you with a tailored user experience. Also, if you have given your approval for the use of cookies, this is remembered in a cookie. As a consequence, you don’t have to re-enter your preferences during each visit resulting in a more comfortable and easier use of the Website. Permanent cookies can be deleted via the settings of your web browser.

#### Session cookies

By using session cookies we can monitor which parts of the Website you have viewed during a visit. This helps us to adjust our services as much as possible for the benefit of the visitors. These cookies are automatically deleted after each visit.

#### Tracking cookies

We do not make use of any tracking cookies which could enable us to monitor whether you also visited other websites within our network.

#### Google analytics

Through the Website a cookie is placed by Google as part of its ‘Analytics’ service. We use this service to monitor how visitors use the Website. Google might provide such information to third parties to comply with statutory legal obligations or to third parties who process such information on behalf of Google.

The information gathered by Google will be made anonymous as much as possible. Your IP address will not be provided. The information will be transferred to the United States and saved on servers in the United States. Google has indicated to comply with the Safe Harbor principles and joined the Safe Harbor Program of the U.S. Department of Commerce. This means that an adequate standard for privacy protection of the processing of any possible processing of personal data under EU law should exist.

#### Social media buttons

On the Website buttons are included to promote (“like”) or share (“tweet”) websites on social networks. These buttons function by means of programming code of these social networks. If these buttons are used, cookies are stored on your computer. This is not within our control. Please read the privacy statements of such social networks, which may be updated frequently, to understand how they process your data acquired via these cookies.

#### Right of access, correction or deletion of your data

You have the right to request access, correction or deletion of your data collected through the use of cookies. For such a request, please send a letter to P.O.Box 2050, 2132 GL  Hoofddorp, The Netherlands and within 4 weeks we will respond to your request. To prevent misuse we might ask you to adequately identify yourself. If you request access to personal data linked to a cookie, you must send us a copy of the relevant cookie, which can be found via your web browser preferences.

#### Activation, deactivation and deletion of cookies

More information with regard to activation, deactivation and deletion of cookies can be found in the instructions via the help-functionality of your web browser.

#### More information on cookies

On the following website more information on cookies can be found:  
Your Online Choices: “A guide to online behaviourial advertising” (www.youronlinechoices.com)

#### Responsible for data provided to us

The Website is owned and operated by Omron Healthcare Europe B.V. All the data you provide us through this web site will be held in a database maintained by Omron Healthcare Europe B.V. in the Netherlands.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

#### Uses made of the information

We may use information held about you in the following ways:  
-To ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer  
-To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.  
\- To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.  
\- To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.  
\- To notify you about changes to our service.  
\- We may also use your data to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we may contact you about these.

#### Disclosure of your information

Your personal data may be disclosed to our affiliated companies established in the EMEA region for the purposes of sending you promotional information about our products or services. We may disclose your personal data to any member of the Omron group, including, but not limited to, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries.

We may disclose your personal data to third parties:  
-In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.  
-If Omron or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.  
-If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation.

#### Your rights

If you wish to know, correct and supplement or delete or block the personal data that Omron holds about you or if you wish to register an objection in connection with your particular personal circumstances or if you would like to unsubscribe from any Omron mailing list, please contact us by email or by regular mail using the contact details at the bottom of this privacy and cookie policy. Omron will use reasonable efforts to honor your request, or objection, or inform you as to whether and, if so, to what extent it is complying therewith within 4 weeks after we receive such request or objection.

The Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

#### Changes to our privacy and cookie policy

Omron may revise this privacy and cookie policy at any time at its own discretion and without notice by updating this posting. You should check the Website from time to time to review the then current privacy and cookie policy. Certain provisions of this privacy and cookie policy notice may be superseded by expressly designated legal notices or terms located on particular pages at the Website.

#### Governing law

This privacy and cookie policy shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of The Netherlands. Disputes arising in connection with this privacy and cookie policy shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Dutch courts.

#### Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy and cookie policy are welcomed and should be sent by regular mail to: Omron Healthcare Europe B.V., Marketing and Communication Department, Scorpius 33, 2132LR, Hoofddorp, The Netherlands.
